Zee Hossain

System Engineer, Duke Energy, Robinson Nuclear Plant

Upper Darby, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Zee-Hossain/7e58653191c7d72b

I&C Electrical Engineering Specialist with experience in, Duke Energy and Worley Parsons I&C/Electrical Nuclear Engineering Division. Gained Unescorted access to Robinson Nuclear Power Plant to work as an I&C System Engineer. Experience in Worley Parsons Engineering, instrument evaluation involved with extended power uprate (EPU), schematics, and process and instrumentation diagrams (P&ID). Passport software, Access Data Base, ETAP, Cable sizing calculation, and Relay procedure to perform plant modification work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer, Duke Energy, Robinson Nuclear Plant

Instrument and Controls - Hartsville, SC - 2013 to 2015

Robinson Nuclear Plant (RNP)-Hartsville, SC. Performed and gained unescorted access to Robinson nuclear plant (RNP) as a system engineer. Performed work as an Electrical I&C System Engineer on different system which are Loose Parts Monitoring (LPMS) system, Inadequate Core Cooling Monitoring (ICCM)/RVLIS system, Annunciator System, and AMSAC systems. Worked on during R028 outage for testing and verifying A, B, C battery system. Gained experience on nuclear procedure of Battery testing for A, B, and C train battery during the outage of Robinson Power Plant (RNP).Familiarity, with the Passport, EDB software to perform work in the Robinson Nuclear Power Plant.

(I&C) Electrical Engineering Specialist

Instrument and Controls - Reading, PA - 2012 to 2013

Florida Power Corporation (FPC) - Crystal River Unit 3. Identified each instruments of different systems located into the power plant according to the existing WorleyParsons design base (DBD), engineering change (EC) documents, instrument specification sheets, schematics and process and instrumentation diagrams (P&ID) documents for instruments evaluation in EPU condition. Collected, organized, documented, and updated Access database and Passport software that form the basis of the support for the WorleyParsons design Engineering Team for EPU work.

Virgil C. (V.C) Summer Nuclear Generating Station, South Carolina- Performed cable tray fill justification calculation to do cable sizing and integration into the power plant. Consulted with senior engineer as a daily basis to perform cable sizing and Ampacity calculation. Determined and verified the temperature of the cable in the power plant environment to perform calculation.

Philadelphia Power and Light (PPL) Corporation, Allentown, PA- Performed Sudden Pressure Relay(SPR) calibration calculation procedure according to the NEPM-QA-0221 nuclear procedure. Identified and marked up the drawing to do Modification (Mod) work for that particular relay, created a new connection drawing, and determined the color coding of the cable to connect the device to the plant.

Engineering Assistant (Co-Op)

Exelon Power - Kennett Square, PA - 2008 to 2008

Consulted with senior engineers to perform electrical testing of motors and generators. Collaborated with senior engineers in writing testing procedure relays and circuit breaker. Identified practical application behind each testing theory. Calibrated and replaced electromechanical-based relays by utilizing relay coordination study. Performed trip testing (relays and breaker) in 199-MW power plant. Completed safety training related to power plant operation.

Network Associate

Comcast Corporation - West Chester, PA - 2007 to 2007

Engineering and Scientific Assistant (Co-Op), Pennsylvania Department of Transportation

Cable Division - King of Prussia, PA - 2006 to 2006

Re-imaged new computers, and shipped the firewall and networking equipment in the address provided by the network engineers. Participated and contributed to the day-to-day support of the Cable Division across many areas, which included WAN monitoring and management, maintenance escalation and restoral processes, technical documentation, and change management. Possessed the administrative expertise to collect, organize, document, and update the various tracking systems that form the basis of the support for the Team.

2006 Engineering and Scientific Assistant (Co-Op), Pennsylvania Department of Transportation, King of Prussia, Pennsylvania

Worked on construction site as a Field Inspector. Collaborated with team of three to inspect highway system (i.e., guide rails, sign structure, and tree pruning). Recorded and summarized work completed by contractors to submit for review.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA 2011

SKILLS

Power/Utilities Sector (5 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Senior Design Project

- Designed and built a Portable Solar System
- · Identified solar panels to compatible with the battery
- Developed test plans and procedures to test and verify the sealed lead acid (SLA) battery with different loads according to the solar system size
- Identified each components and developed specifications for the system
- Researched solar energy and gained practical experience about solar power and production systems